This is a big opportunity for steel. In
the end, you will need kilometers of
tube.
When there's a gold rush, sell shovels.
When there's a hyperloop rush, sell
steel.
Hi. Oh, no. Virgin Hyperloop One is
shutting down. Oh, no. Who could have
foreseen that Hyperloop wouldn't have
worked?
Of course, every engineer
with half a brain cell who wasn't
invested in financially invested in the
idea.
High-speed train company, Hyperloop One
shuts down. Elon Musk much hyped
Hyperloop One, even though he had
nothing to do with it. It was Virgin
Hyperloop, and now and then once Virgin
pulled out, it was called Hyperloop One.
They're shutting down. Hyperloop One is
shutting down, ending a literal
transportation pipe dream.
The Hyperloop is dead, for real this
time. Yes, breaking news. It's finally
dead, and I have done some videos on
this. I did one main channel one on the
TransPod Flux Jet.
550 million-dollar boondoggle. That was
an absolute joke. But, there's been many
different Hyperloops. I've done some
second channel videos on the Hyperloop
as well, and it's just
Come on. Come on. It was never going to
work. But, anyway, let's go through it.
The Hyperloop is dead. Hyperloop One,
formerly Virgin Hyperloop, is reportedly
selling off its assets, laying off its
remaining workers, and preparing to shut
down by the end of 2023. It was a dream
too impossible for this world. Oh, no.
Maybe on Mars it'll happen. Maybe on the
moon. Hyperloop One, the futuristic
transportation startup that promised to
whisk us through nearly airless tubes at
airline speeds, is shutting down,
according to Bloomberg. The company is
selling off its assets, closing down its
offices, and laying off employees. It
will formally close at the end of the
year, at which point all its
intellectual property shifted to a
majority stakeholder major Dubai port
operator DB uh DP World. And yes, you
remember this one?
Dubai's Hyperloop. Uh this is just from
July 2023. They were still hyping this
up. Dubai's Hyperloop project
revolutionizing transportation in the
city. And I've like tweeted uh stuff
like this. I'm not sure if I covered it
on my second channel, but they released
all this fancy animation about this
Hyperloop in Dubai and they'll teaming
up with uh Virgin Hyperloop at at the
time. And that was announced in 2016.
Wow.
So, I think they've come a gutser. I
think this project's come a gutser as
well um along with
Hyperloop. So, it was supposed to be
launched in 2027 or 2028. I love this.
Whoever buys the test track in the
Nevada desert will have one hell of a
slip and slide if they want it.
Don't know about slip and slide, but uh
cuz it's like it's going to be uh
parallel. So, here's the 500-m test
track they built in the Nevada desert.
And they they actually put uh two people
on it. Um there it is. It looks pretty
funky, doesn't it?
It was never going to work. It was never
going to work. Just the mo- I won't even
go through the mo- to just like
We're going to survive. The first humans
in a Hyperloop. It was just never going
to work for human transportation. You
know, maybe maybe at a stretch you could
kludge it together for uh
transporting goods and stuff like that
that doesn't have all the you know,
doesn't have the problem with people
dying. There is
Oh, and we're slowing down.
And that was it.
That was the entire trip.
So, yeah, they're the um they were two
executive co-founder and chief
technology
and CTO, yeah.
Woo!
Yeah! And they're no longer with the
company. There's just a few remaining
people to sell off the assets and that's
it. Sorry, I wonder what they're doing
now.
If you know, leave it in the comments.
And there he goes,
one and only passenger Hyperloop test.
Got the nice purple rings on there to
make it look pretty funky, but there you
go. They did did actually
Hyperloop's entire
entire existence, they put two people
through a little 500 m test track. Oh my
goodness. And people don't know, they
think Elon Musk is actually behind all
this. He just like sort of rehashed the
concept back in you know, it's an
ancient concept going back like 100
years or something. And he just rehashed
it and then wrote it and wrote and
released a white paper in 2013. So over
a decade now. Um and then he like Tesla
did actually provide some funding for
some student groups to do the test and
stuff like that. But even that's been
removed now. All that test track and
they don't do that anymore. And here's
the MIT Hyperloop and they just you
know, and it's good fun for the student
teams. But that's actually all that Elon
Musk had to do with any of these
Hyperloop companies. He had nothing to
do with Hyperloop One or you know, any
of the other Hyperloop companies that
sprung up. Because you know,
money was just
milk like cash cow.
Milk the investment cash cow of all you
know, once you release that white paper,
the hype train was on, right? And then
all this investment money just flowed in
and all these companies just started up
and just milk that cash cow, took the
money and yeah, they've all gone bust.
It's just ridiculous. So yeah, but
they're formally they are gone. They are
formally gone as of in a couple of days
time, the last remaining person who's
selling off the assets, presumably you
can buy the Nevada desert test track.
That'd be fun.
What would you leave it in the comments
down below? Imagine if you could buy
that for
like a couple of grand or something. I'd
buy it. If I was in Nevada, I'd buy it
and just I don't know, do something with
it, right? like
it's probably worth more as scrap metal,
right? So, um but yeah, I'd please, if
you know and like if there's any details
of this, there's got to actually be
details of this somewhere of auctioning
off the stuff here cuz they're
liquidating the assets of the company.
So, leave it in the comments down below
if you can find any info on that. I'm
not going to go searching, but yeah.
It'd be cool if somebody could buy the
test track, wouldn't that be great?
Since it's founded in 2014, the company
raised 450 million bucks down the
gurgler in venture capital funds and
other investments. Well, there's still a
small smattering of startups trying to
build hyperloops. The demise of one of
the biggest hyperloop company signals
the end of the dream that originated
with his uh white paper in 20 alpha
paper in 2013.
And he called it the fifth mode of
transportation and it was never going to
work. There's just so many issues with
it.
But like
no, no, no, I'm not going to start going
into the issues. The engineer and it's
not just a matter of oh, it just apply
more dollars and the engineering
problems uh solve themselves. No, some
ideas are just fundamentally stupid. You
don't do them. Like UBeam, like solar
roadways. Yeah, you can kind of sort of
kludge something together that works,
but it's never ever going to be
practical. So, just don't bother. It's
just it's just an absolute boondoggle.
And Australia was not immune to this as
well. So, I'm just embarrassed as the
rest of you. Hyperloop One
gone bust building a 40 billion dollar
hyperloop in Australia by 2021. Uh
it's 20 it's the end of 2023.
Didn't happen. Oops. Ultra Australia,
the official Australian representative
Hyperloop One has flagged plans to have
a functioning Hyperloop in Australia.
The proposed route of the Australian
Hyperloop would be between Sydney and
Melbourne cuz that's really the only two
places you want to go in Australia.
Pretty much. Um to achieve this uh they
would send commuter and freight pods
flying in a depressurized tube at speeds
in excess of 1,000 km an hour. And their
vice president talked about a uh spoke
about Australia as a testing ground for
the Hyperloop. Never happened. Oh, there
you go. Melbourne to Sydney is the third
busiest air corridor in the world. It
can give you Melbourne to downtown
Sydney in 55 minutes.
Yeah, no. It is expected that a
Hyperloop from Melbourne to Sydney would
cost anywhere up to $40 billion.
Uh
yeah, and our NBN network system here,
internet, well, our nationwide internet
was only supposed to cost like 20
billion.
No. Because they operate in
pressure-reduced environment, it'll cost
next to nothing to move from one city to
another. Next to nothing.
From Dr. Alan James here. It costs next
to nothing to transfer in energy costs
or any other cost to transport you from
Sydney to Melbourne in one of these
Hyperloop boom doggles.
What's that you can smell?
Yeah, I wonder if Australian
venture capitalist Philip Kingston,
never heard of him, believes the
Hyperloop One is now time to move on
such a project. He's even on the record
willing to stump up some funding. I
wonder if he ever stumped up the funding
for it.
Like even Engineers Australia, right?
That's our formal engineering body here
in Australia. Even they got in and like
hosted uh the general manager from
Hyperloop design, Richard McFallon, as a
uh speaker of, you know, like come on,
seriously? What next? Engineers
Australia are going to host the uh Bruce
Sols talking about the solar freaking
roadways here in Australia?
The company was also perpetually
strapped for cash. Branson helped secure
a new $50 million investment from two
existing investors, which helped meet
payroll obligations. The company raised
$172 million in new funding in 2019, 90
million of which came from DP World,
which has previously invested $25
million in company already has two seats
on the startup's board of directors. The
company made several important strides,
including building that test track we
saw in the Nevada desert and
conducted its first test. The pod only
reached a top speed of 100 miles an
hour, far short of the original promise
of seven times that amount. Critics
said, that's us, that while Hyperloop
may be technically feasible, it still
only amounts to vaporware. It's been
called a utopian vision that would be
financially impossible to achieve. It's
one of those technologies that it is
also just around the corner, according
to its boost to its boosters. Oh,
they're called boosters now, are they?
Oh, that's a new one.
Despite outwardly appearing to still be
years away from completion in 2017,
Virgin Hyperloop's top executive told
The Verge they expect to see working
Hyperloops around the world by 2020. And
how many times have we seen this? Oh,
yeah, we're going to have self-driving
cars and full self-driving and we're
going to have everything. We're going to
be on Mars. We're going to be doing this
and that and we're going to be doing No.
No. No. And anyone could see the exact
same thing with Hyperloop. It's It's not
just a matter of throwing money at it
and it magically happening. It's a
fundamentally impractical solution. It's
ridiculous. During the pandemic, nearly
all of the top executives and founders
left Hyperloop One. I guess they had a
lot of time sitting at home pondering.
Oh jeez, yeah, this thing's really not
going to work. I really should
I really should be changing jobs right
about now. They also shed Virgin from
the name after the company decided to
change over to passenger trips in favor
of cargo. Oh, let's have a look at that.
There you go. Switches focus on
passengers to cargo as it lays off half
its staff and that was in February 2022.
So, they couldn't even make it work with
cargo. They got nowhere with cargo
because
if you're just like, "Okay, you've taken
humans out of the loop." Okay, not a
good idea. Watch WarGames, okay? Keep
humans in the loop, please. Not this AI
rubbish.
They couldn't even make it work. I
wonder what happens to this prototype
passenger pod. Could you buy it? Is
there some liquidation sale? Like, is
there like an auction sale somewhere?
Can you pony up like 100 bucks and then
it's yours? Take it away if you can move
it.
That'd be hilarious.
If I had the space and I had the ability
to transport, I'd get that just for
kicks.
Make a great background for the videos.
The scale of the redundancy was
definitely not expected. You think? They
told the Financial Times that recent
cuts would allow the company to respond
in a more agile and nimble way and a
more cost-efficient manner and that the
decision to lose so many staff at once
not been taken lightly. Said the
changing focus to freight over
passengers really has more to do with
global supply chain issues and all the
changes due to COVID. So, they're just
like
when they think like, "Where's the wind
blowing these days where we can milk
more potential money from?" And
no, not passengers. No, cargo, cargo.
Let's chase that ferry. Oh, there you
go. DP World have a 76 76% stake. It's
abundantly clear that potential
customers are interested in cargo while
passenger is somewhat far further away.
Focusing on pallets is easier to do.
There is less risk for a passenger and
less of a regulatory process. You think?
They had 15 potential customers lined
up.
I wonder if they've all
if they've all buggered off now for this
yes, the Dubai
cargo hyperloop
thing. They're like, "Here it is, you
know, cargo." It's just like cargo
speed. They just drop on there and
whoosh out of the tunnels just like in
the Thunderbirds. Just checking in on
the TransPod flux jet here. Breaking
news, breaking news on their website.
Brussels welcomes the world's first
Hyperloop Association,
October 2023.
Seriously? I got to read that. And the
last
post was how they in February 2023, how
the transport system beats the
profitability. So they're just, you
know, wanking on there about their own
tech. What is this? Brussels, seven
leading international Hyperloop
companies have gathered in Brussels with
industry institutions and the research
community to kick off the Hyperloop
Association. First organization
committed to advancing the emerging
Hyperloop industry. Emerging?
I think it's crashed and burned towards
commercialization. The associa- So
they're only forming an association
months before version one
version I believe Hyperloop one,
whatever they're calling themselves, has
just gone completely tits up.
Great timing. The association's founding
members including H1, Hard Hard
Hyperloop, Hyperloop TT,
Nevomo, Swiss Pod Technologies,
TransPod, and Zeleros, all the hard
hitting ones, held the inaugural
ceremony in the Espace Chenier. During
the event, they officially introduced
the organization extending an open
invitation to globally global industry
stakeholders and partners to join its
mission. The hyperloopassociation.org.
I wonder if there's some photos or video
of the event. That was just two months
ago, right?
A vote of confidence from visionary
leaders in European transportation.
Yeah, it looks like they have people
from the European Commission there, the
trans- the cab- transport cabinet member
or something like that. Unified vision
for the future, wank wank wank wank
wank. Hyperloop Association members,
they couldn't even get the biggest one.
Hyperloop One was the biggest one. It's
gonski. It is absolutely gonski. Um and
so board of directors, uh
Nevoma Nevomo, he's the president. Um,
what? Hard hyperloop? Oh, no, there you
go. Hyperloop one. Okay, interim CEO and
board member
Hyper He's from Hyperloop one. Well,
he's Gonsky now. Zeleros hyperloop,
haven't heard of them. TransPod, of
course, we have covered that. SwissPod
and Hard hyperloop I've heard of.
Nevomo, I don't think I've heard of.
Nevomo, looks like
Nevomo hyperloop. Looks like they're
back in the trend. Um, a new inno-
maglev. A new innovative world's first
levitating train on existing
infrastructure. None of this
evacuated tube rubbish.
How to implement magnetic rail in
Europe. So, they're
They've gone just recently, as 17th of
October, right? They've gone for maglev.
It's a high-speed
And check out this guy here. He's just
going, "Yeah, nah, this is bullshit."
And this dude here with the side eye,
he's not buying it either. Gone.
One day travel on existing
Anyway, this is less because
it's actually
maglev. I've I've been on that maglev at
430 km/h. I've been on the Shanghai
maglev. It was great. It works. 430
km/h. It's an energy hog and it didn't
go anywhere. It really didn't go
anywhere of value, but you know, it's
it works. So, it looks like
even they've transitioned over just just
a regular
regular maglev, right? And this is like
one of the founding members of the
hyperloop. Hyperloop is just maglev. It
was always going to. I You know,
everyone was calling it from day one.
Everyone who was debunking hyperloop was
saying from day one, "Nah, it's just
going to I- It's either going to go
completely bust or it's just going to be
regular maglev." Like, it's just like
It's just ridiculous. So, it looks like
that's what they're doing. Now, they've
transitioned over.
Oops, there you go. Nevomo. So, that is
no longer Hyperloop. If it's not a
you know, partially evacuated
tube, then it's not Hyperloop. It's No,
it's just it's just maglev or it's rail
in a tunnel. It's unique technology for
a maglev system. A passive passive
magnetic levitation train operating on
existing railway tracks. At speeds of
existing railway tracks. So, you put
something down the middle, do you? Oh,
this this Nevomo thing I think probably
What in in the middle?
In the middle. Yep.
Allow us maglev vehicle to the middle
and the truck by adding the linear motor
in the middle.
They're going to add the linear rail in
the middle. I Yeah, that's That's the
first thing I thought of as that's what
they're going to do. So, it looks like
are they Are they proposing like a test
track or something? And so, they put
that Looks like they have like
full-scale Uh apparently that looks
full-scale prototype they done then.
That looks serious business.
So, they've got some Nevomo, there you
go.
Does it Does it do anything? Come on,
flick flick the switch.
Tektronix oscilloscope spotted. Oh,
yeah. It moved in.
Moves. It moves. So, they haven't gone
to speed. They've just got this little
indoor track. Okay, it's little indoor
test track.
And it just it drags you, right? Okay,
cool. All right. Well, let's see if
anything comes of that. So, who's Hard
Hyperloop? I have heard of them, but I
can't remember. There's been so many of
them and they were just milking the cash
cow. Check it out. This is from 2 days
ago. They're actually building.
They're building European Hyperloop
Center. They're building the European
Hyperloop Center. Here's a time-lapse.
Witness the birth of the European
Hyperloop Center. Starting from the
kickoff event where first two pipe they
were placed. Okay.
Experience the transformation of the
site in the state-of-the-art Hyperloop
test facility.
They've still got money. This is This is
2 days ago. They're building something.
Okay? And it's That looks like Oh, it's
got a branch. It's got a branch.
Wow, look at that. Hyperloop test
center. Wow.
Okay, there's still money flowing into
this. Hyperloop ain't dead yet. Heart
Hyperloop. Where are they getting the I
hope this will be THE FUTURE.
GOOD WATER PIPE, but maybe you'll show
us Hyperloop. Well done. Surprised to
see this grift is still going. I hope
this is funded by private investors and
not with taxes I pay.
When will this grift end?
Hyperscam. Lmao.
Only one comment out of the seven is
positive. And I I'm not sure if it's
sarcasm or not. Yeah, they've they've
done stuff in the last couple of months.
1 year ago, the road map bringing global
Hyperloop plans to reality.
Oh, I think I remember this one. That's
where they're going to build your new
test facility in the mud.
Yep. Yep, that's that's the place.
That's that's where you want it. I'm
guessing the land was cheap.
35 stakeholders.
Can't fail.
Look at this. Whoosh.
These tubes, they have a very high
capacity, the equivalent of 500 trucks
per hour.
500 trucks an hour.
You have the potential of replacing half
of that truck traffic that could maybe
solve already a large part of
Here's their kickoff event.
There you go. European Hyperloop This is
serious business. Rent a crowd.
Ah, we missed it. I didn't get the
invite.
I don't didn't know anyone else. I don't
think Thunderfoot got an invite.
Hyperloop development and we believe
that it will run around Europe and
around the world.
This is first new step of the European
Hyperloop Center is the start of a
really big thing for Hyperloop.
I think the Hyperloop is a great
solution for our mobility challenges of
the of the future.
Got to solve those mobility challenges.
For me it's very important to
It's all about collaboration.
together with all the Hyperloop
companies.
This is a big opportunity for steel. In
the end you will need kilometers of
tube.
When there's When there's a gold rush,
sell shovels. When When there's a
Hyperloop rush, sell steel.
Wow, look at everyone's pouring out. Oh,
look look this is where it's going to
be.
Looks like they're good in a good
location. I'll give it that cuz then
they can extend it
and compare it to rail.
2025 they're talking about. Push the
button and what happens? Smoke. It goes
up in smoke. That was all the investors'
money going up in smoke.
Going up in fireworks. Yay!
Okay, see? They've got like
That looks like they're putting some
work inside that. They're you know. So,
they're serious.
Okay.
Hard Hyperloop might be the new
Hyperloop leaders.
They might be rubbing their hands
together that Hyperloop One's gone bust.
Maybe they're buying the assets up.
Who's Zeleros Hyperloop? Hyperloop's
still happening. Look at it. 2 weeks ago
discover the Hyperloop powertrain
project. Okay.
End-to-end partners contributors tickle.
Wow, there's still money flowing into
this.
Will 2024 be the year that it all
finally sinks
with Hyperloop One is the first one. Oh,
look at that.
That's pretty fancy.
Wow, I love the model.
Wait a nice file. They can go into the
model building
industry. There's
a fair bit of money in that.
That's pretty good.
Electronics parts is building battery
management. Oh, there you go. Look at
this. Oh, yeah. I got some schematic
action.
It's all about the batteries, behavior
of the battery.
I'd I'd be more concerned with the
reduced pressure tube, quite frankly.
Under vacuum.
Oh, there you go. Some inputs, some
outputs. Oh, there we go. Got some
action.
This serious?
They got some funding. They're doing
some engineering work.
Here you go. Zeleros.
Oh.
It's all happening.
Zeleros. Look at this. They're building.
Zeleros are building.
It's all happening.
Come on.
Where's the finished test track?
Look at this.
It was like a mine cart just going back
and forth. I expect to see like Indy in
there.
Hyper track. Zeleros.
Not much action there. So, Swisspod
Technologies. No, Swisspod they're way
behind.
Museum of Transportation. What?
Their tunnel flooded 4 years ago. I got
to see that.
Oh, no. No, it's it's not flooded. It's
just a flat bottom. It looked like it
was water.
But, there you go.
Oh, Swiss Pod Technologies. Look at it.
Oh, yeah. Yeah.
Boom.
Now to our continuing coverage on this
subject, Swiss Pod, the company that's
planning to build and test a full-scale
Hyperloop prototype in Pueblo, took an
early step this week in eventual
construction of that project.
News 5's Andy Cole enjoyed the story
from home and has an update on the
story. Andy?
Yeah, this week the company CEO shared a
photo on Twitter of crews doing some
soil testing work on the Pueblo Plex.
That's probably where that track will be
built. That soil test is going to
provide engineers with some important
data that they need when it comes to
designing and building that full-scale
prototype for the Hyperloop here in
Pueblo. It's just what's happening this
week at the Pueblo Plex.
That prototype will look like this one
that the company built near their
headquarters
CEO Dennis Tutor said that they're
planning an initial test on the
reduced-scale track later this summer, a
first in the Hyperloop industry.
That's a decent
effort though. That's like a full loop.
So the fundamental metrics such as
energy consumption, neutral carbon
footprint, speed,
that those are possible with the hyper
transportation system.
They'll move through a vacuum-sealed
tube reaching near supersonic speeds
with a propulsion system that's designed
to be carbon neutral.
Carbon neutral? Leave it in the comments
down below if your city, if your state,
if your country had plans for a
Hyperloop at one stage. Uh like somebody
pointed me to this transporting Missouri
here, Kansas City. It was supposed to go
to from Kansas City to St. Louis in 30
minutes. And like yeah, nah. Yeah, nah.
There you go. But like there you go,
Hyperloop One. Now it's gone. It's gone,
Skippy. But that's just the Kansas City
local news there covering. Nope, it
shuts down. Nope, it's coming at ya.
Oops. And last one here, who's Hyperloop
Transportation Technologies, Hyperloop
TT. Um yeah, okay. Yeah, I've heard of
them. Express freight. They're going
into the freight business.
No this uh human rubbish. Don't need to
transport humans anymore cuz we're just
going to be living in our pods and
eating the bugs and that's it.
Express freight. Uh we just got wanky
Yeah, okay. So here's their So this is
just a month ago, right?
Hyperloop Express freight. They're all
moving to freight
cuz they know it's not going to work uh
for us mushy humans.
And yeah, nah. Capture the right So they
come down and convey about and then they
push them on. Dock door opening. What?
And then they push them in and then they
go well and then it comes out and then
yep, yep. They look like um standard
airline um
pod things, the ones that go on
airlines, aren't they? I'm pretty sure
they they look like the ones that go on
airlines. I'm sure that's the idea of
that. But uh yeah, nah.
Designed by Tangerine. Is then just pay
money to them and they'll produce your
wanky graphics for you and Bob's your
uncle, you can milk another round of
funding. So Hyperloop One, we're on the
board of directors um here, but were
they in the members? Oh, H1, formerly
Hyperloop One. Okay. So these are on the
Hyperloop Association is still a thing
and uh they've still got a board of
directors and they're still company, but
who So who's the current winner? It
might be Hart Hyperloop cuz they're
actually like just doing stuff cuz just
as little as 2 months ago they were
having like a this big thing and they've
obviously got money, they're still
building, but there you go. Place your
bets down below. Will uh Hart Hyperloop
make it through 2024
funding runs out
before everyone realizes that this is a
complete and epic boondoggle. Um no,
sorry. Uh Hyperloop is never going to be
a thing either for passengers or for
cargo. It might they might call it
Hyperloop and it might just be maglev
maglev, right? It's just going to be a
maglev thing. But that's not hyperloop.
Hyperloop is the reduced air pressure uh
tube. Yeah, nah. It's not going to
happen.
Switches focus from passengers to cargo
as it lays off staff. No, they've all
completely come a cropper and uh yep,
I'd be surprised if the other companies
uh survive 2024. But anyway, there you
go. Hyperloop is dead for realsies.
It's gone skint. Who could have
predicted it?
Just like any engineer with half a brain
could have predicted it. So, a hearty
salute to Hyperloop One, the biggest
hyperloop company out there for trying.
It was a valiant effort, but nah, it's
come a cropper. They've gone under.
Anyway, I hope you enjoyed that video.
If you did, give it a big thumbs up and
as always, discuss down below.
Catch you next time.